Prithviraj Kadiyala

Contact no.: +1 405 227 6525

Email ID: prithvirajkadiyala@ou.edu | prithvirajkadiyala@gmail.com

Career Objective

Graduate Research Assistant with 2+ years of experience Leading Team in Designing and developing website using various algorithms to solve the problem of Data Management for US Department of Agriculture while understanding key features of Business approach towards commercializing product. Team lead for designing and developing of Network Management Systems using Cisco Packet Tracer simulation tool. Looking to utilize Developer, Time management and Team Leading skill in the position of Software Development Engineer/Full-Stack Developer.

Education

Masters of Computer Engineering, 2016-2018*
University of Oklahoma, Oklahoma, USA (Expected Graduation Dec 3.17/4 2018)

Bachelor of Engineering Electronics & Communication BVBCET, Hubballi, India. 8.57/10

2012-2016

Technical Skills

- Webpage designing (JavaScript, AJAX, CSS, HTML5, SQLite3, Python, Flask).
- Arduino Coding, Micro-controller coding and C-programming.
- MATLAB software for plotting and visualizing equations.
- Used R programming to analyze Big-Data
- Photoshop for designing posters, banners and certificates.
- Designed VLSI circuits using Cadence software.

Experience

Research Assistant at OU – 2016-Present

Leading a team of 5 to Design and develop Website for Database Management at *US Department of Agriculture*. Proposing and developing solutions based on the interactions with Animal Scientists and Veterinarians. Experience the Business aspect of conducting research. Product Testing before launch.

Team Lead at BVBCET July 2015-May 2016

Study different RFCs (Request for Communications) available for different routing systems. Study the OIDs (Object Identifiers) required for NMS. Configuring routing devices and routing protocols. Build a Network Management System.

BoredBees Pvt Ltd – May 2014-Dec 2014

This internship was based on the Java programming skills and the development of Android Apps. I learnt to develop android apps which are market ready using the Eclipse software which helps to emulate the android software virtually.

Projects

- 1. 3D modeling and fabrication of a "**Bluetooth Speaker**" as a part of Product Development and Realization (PDR).
- 2. Designed and built a prototype model for "Intelligent Alerting and Braking system" as a part of 6th sem project.
- 3. Built an Android App named "Gesture controlled Music player" as a part of 5th sem project.
- 4. Built a Windows App named "**INDIAN GODS**" as a part of workshop conducted by windows in 2012-2013.
- 5. Designed and built a "Solar Lantern" as a part of Social Innovation during Bachelor's.
- 6. Designed and built PCBs using the **Eagle, Autotrax** and **Express PCB** software as a part of self-assessment in 3rd and 4th sem.

Achievements

- Achieved 2nd prize in Analog maker competition held by Texas Instruments India in 2014.
- Helped in the web page designing of the National Tech-fest, Pleiades 2015.
- Paper presented at the Indian Technology Congress-2015, Bangalore.
- Paper presented at the All India IEEE Meet- 2015, Bhimavaram.
- Attended workshops on Hacking Expert (Level 1.0) and Android App Development in NITK,
 Suratkal.

Extracurricular activities

- Junior head of Paper\Poster presentation and Registration committee.
- Volunteered for Electro-fantasy, Roborace and Robowars events in the Pleiades 2015.
- Volunteered for Marathon'13 and Marathon'14.
- Organized the event Gamers' Valley in the National Tech-fest Pleiades 2015.
- Organized an event Gaming Carnival under EA association in 2014.
- Organized the workshops of Spoken Tutorials under MHRD initiative of free video lectures of IIT-Bombay for years 2013-14 & 2014-15.
 - Latex, Python, Scilab, C\C++, GeoGebra, Libre Office, MySQL
- Volunteered for Spell-A-Thon under BVB-IEEE in Oct 2014.
- Organized MathStar'13 & MathStar'14 under BVB-IEEE.
- Active member of BVB-IEEE.

Social

Website – https://prithvirajkadiyala.github.io/

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/prithviraj-kadiyala-003073a3

Github - https://github.com/prithvirajkadiyala